<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Nicolas Deutschmann</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Nicolas Deutschmann</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Worst-case scenario for a model ensemble</title>
      <link>/posts/worst_ensemble/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/worst_ensemble/</guid>
      <description>Introduction It&amp;rsquo;s part of machine learning &amp;ldquo;folk wisdom&amp;rdquo; that ensembles of models are a good way to really optimize your prediction and getting the most of your data. Kaggle competitions are often won by ensembles, and there are some theoretical guarantees that make you fell good about them (although their hypotheses are never verified in real life). In practice, it&amp;rsquo;s definitely mostly a good idea to use ensembles; they most often improve performance and provide some ways to estimate uncertainty by checking the agreement of the different models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monte Carlo Integrals over $\mathbb{R}$</title>
      <link>/posts/monte_carlo_infinite/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/monte_carlo_infinite/</guid>
      <description>Monte Carlo integration provides a way to compute integrals numerically with an algorithm that has the same convergence class (uncertainty $\sim \mathcal{O}(1/\sqrt{N})$ ) independently of the dimension of the integration domain (as opposed to methods like the trapezoid approximation).
Integrating over a finite volume is quite easy: you need to find a parametrization of your domain such that each variable spans a fixed interval and one can then rely on any strictly probability distribution over this interval to sample points.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
